Raphael Tomé Santana

Senior PHP Developer

Pelotas, RS - Brazil | +5553991562219 | raphaelts3@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/raphael-tomé-santana-8b402364

Summary

Developer with 9+ years of expertise having passed through an online gaming firm, an agriculture specialist company, a startup e-commerce pioneer in Dropshipping in Brazil, and, currently, working as a PHP Developer and Mentor for an international outsourcing company.

Work experience

Mentor 2019-11

BairesDev, Mentoring

- Key Qualifications & Responsibilities
 - Helping other developers to improve their performance analyzing how they handle their code, tasks and team communication.

PHP Developer

2019-02 - Present

BairesDev, Connexient

- Key Qualifications & Responsibilities
 - o Supporting the internal data flow for more than 20 hospitals
 - Responsible for creating and configuring new hospitals
 - Actively communicator with both data and mobile teams
- Key IT Achievements
 - Improved the performance of one of the higher cost processes from 10+ minutes for large data sets to <2 minutes for even larger data sets by refactoring the code with better logic and cleaner code.
 - Developed a one-click process to clone an old client configuration for a new one, improving the whole process for configuring a new client from more than a day to a maximum of 3 hours.
 - Refactored a core part of the process from static arrays to Redis which was one of the couple parts missing to enable the change from a large single server to a few small ones.

PHP Developer 2018-11 - 2019-02

BairesDev, Victor's Gold

- Key Qualifications & Responsibilities
 - In charge of two of the core projects
 - o An active voice for architectural and technology decisions for all projects
- Key IT Achievements
 - Build a system responsible to handle all the communication between projects, written in Javascript(Node.JS) this project was the orchestrator of the product flow from start to winner/loser notifications.
 - Rebuild the system that managed the internal currency used on the product, written in PHP 7 with Zend 3 this project was responsible for all the internals currencies transactions.
 - Shared info between different databases to make the most of each. The external project backend was supported by MySQL and Redis, the communication system was using mainly Redis, while the currency project was backed by MongoDB and

Skills

PHP

PHP 5.6, 7.0, 7.1, 7.2

MySQL

MySQL 5.5, 5.6, 5.7, 8

JavaScript

ES6, ES7, ES8

Node.JS

Node v8, v10, v12

Cache

Redis, Memcached, Varnish

DevOps

Git, CI/CD, AWS, Docker, GCloud

Tests

IS: Macha Chair DUD: DUDI Init Pahati

JS: Mocha, Chai; PHP: PHPUnit, Behat; C++: CPPUnit

(++

C++ 11,14,17

C++ 11,14,17

ElasticSearch

Floris County F. C

ElasticSearch 5, 6

GoLang

Co.1.121

Go 1.13+

Semi-Senior System Analyst MadeiraMadeira, IT Logistic

2017-10 - 2018-11

- Key Qualifications & Responsibilities
 - Manage more than a hundred transporter companies.
 - o Build scalable and consistent systems for the back office.
 - Assisted the team to bring the best solution to the problems of the company.
- Key IT Achievements
 - Build a crawler in Node.JS that scrapes all the transporters the company works with, duplicating the number of relevant data for each order and reducing the complaints about order information by 80%.
 - Managed to build high availability and scalable system using Elasticsearch, PHP 7+ and Redis, with a hexagonal architecture, which improves the system performance by 200%.

Semi-Senior System Analyst

2017-04 - 2017-09

Kuhlmann Tecnologia & Monitoramento Agrícola, IT

- Key IT Achievement
 - Maintained legacy application using PHP 5 with Zend Framework 1, Bootstrap and Apache.
 - Built a new project using PHP 7 with Laravel 5, Kendo UI and NGINX.
 - Designed a solid cache layer using Memcached and Redis to support a MySQL database.

Leader Developer

2016-12 - 2017-04

WYD2BOT

- Key Qualifications & Responsibilities
 - o Build highly configurable, scalable and high-performance BOT.
- Key IT Achievements
 - o Managed to build a high-performance BOT, using C++, Assembly, and Python, which do everything that a regular client does, but using 95% fewer resources.
 - Released the project as an open-source project.

Development Lead

2011 - 2016-07

Star Destiny

- Key Qualifications & Responsibilities
 - Build highly configurable, scalable and high-performance multiplayer online game.
 - o Build a consistent website for players manages their accounts.
- Key IT Achievements
 - Managed to build a high-performance game server, using C++, Assembly, which improve the game performance in 80%, allowing the same server machine to support 5x more clients.
 - Rebuilt data server which was based on binary files to a new one using MySQL, making possible to update the website to PHP 5 with several upgrades to user interaction with in-game data.

Education

Computer Engineering Universidade Federal de Pelotas 2011 - 2015



